# MUHAMMAD SULTAN

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: 03113696218 Email: m.shykh@outlook.com Linkdin: linkedin.com/in/muhammadsultan-62b447143 Address: Garden East, Karachi, Pakistan

# PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an emerging software engineer, looking to apply my problem-solving and technical skills in a challenging environment. I am a level 1 seller at Fiver with 1-year of experience in freelancing. I am fluent in full-stack web development with core PHP, ORACLE, and SQL SERVER. Eager to help companies with emerging obstacles.

# TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Hands on experience in full stack web development and database design with:

- HTML
- jQuery
- Ajax
- PHP
- ASP.NET MVC
- C#
- MySQL
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Oracle SQL Database
- MongoDB
- Angular Js
- UmbracoCMS
- Microsoft Office
- Version Control using Git
- OOP
- Debugging

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **FREELANCER**

Upwork | Feb 2021 to Present https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~012daa6e0ageg63307

#### LEVEL 1 SELLER

Fiverr | Nov 2019 to Present https://www.fiverr.com/sultanshaikh77

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN**

Nanosoft Technologies | 9-12-20 to 26-03-20

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Intellexal Solutions Private Limited 10-06-2019 to 28-06-2019

## OTHER SKILLS

- The ability to analyze complex technical information
- Can analyze, design and implement database structures
- Detail oriented
- Excellent problem solver

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

# MEHRAN UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY Bachelor of Software Engineering, 2020 CGPA: 3.84

- Coursework in web development, database management, object-oriented programming in java, android programming.

## **PROJECTS**

- Web Portal for Teacher Welfare Council
- ATM Project on Java
- Face Recognition System on Python
- My Portfolio Website
- OPS Law WebApp
- Online Student Portal on Android
- Student Consultancy Web App
- Student Management System on Java

## LICENSE AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Freelancing | Digiskills.pk
- Building Web Applications in PHP | Coursera
- Projects in Csharp | Eduonix Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd
- Wordpress | Digiskills.pk